I have been teaching for a long time,
أنا ادرس منذ مدة طويلة
and in doing so
ومن خلال قيامي بذلك
have acquired a body of knowledge about kids and learning
تعلمت الكثير عن التعليم وعن الاطفال
that I really wish more people would understand
وانا اتمنى فعلا ان تتوسع دائرة الاشخاص
about the potential of students.
الذي يتفهمون الامكانيات الموجودة في الاطفال
In 1931, my grandmother --
في عام 1931 .. جدتي وهي تلك
bottom left for you guys over here --
التي تظهر في اسفل الصورة من الجهة اليسرى على القرب من الشباب
graduated from the eighth grade.
تركت التعليم بعد الصف الثامن
She went to school to get the information
وكانت تذهب الى المدرسة لكي تحصل على المعلومات
because that's where the information lived.
لانه حينها كانت المدارس هي المصدر الوحيد للمعلومات
It was in the books; it was inside the teacher's head;
فقد كانت في الكتب .. وفي أدمغة المدرسين
and she needed to go there to get the information,
لذا فقد احتاجت ان تذهب الى المدرسة لكي تحصل على المعلومات
because that's how you learned.
لانه هكذا يتعلم المرء
Fast-forward a generation:
وبالنظر الى الجيل الذي تلاه
this is the one-room schoolhouse, Oak Grove,
وهذه صورة لاحدى المدارس .. اواك جروف
where my father went to a one-room schoolhouse.
حيث تعلم والدي في غرفة مدرسية
And he again had to travel to the school
وكان يتوجب عليه ايضا كما والدته
to get the information from the teacher,
الذهاب الى المدرسة للحصول على المعلومات
stored it in the only portable memory he has, which is inside his own head,
والتي كانت مخزنة في دماغ المدرس .. كما لو انه ذاكرة متنقلة
and take it with him,
ويتوجب الحصول على المعلومات منها
because that is how information was being transported
وهكذا كان تتتناقل المعلومات
from teacher to student and then used in the world.
من رأس المدرس الى الطالب .. لكي يستخدمها في العالم المحيط به
When I was a kid,
وعندما كنت طفلة
we had a set of encyclopedias at my house.
كان لدينا مجموعة موسوعية في منزلنا
It was purchased the year I was born,
وقد تم شراءها في يوم ولادتي
and it was extraordinary,
وكانت رائعة جداً
because I did not have to wait to go to the library to get to the information.
لانه حينها لم يكن يتوجب علي الذهاب الى المكتبة للحصول على المعلومات
The information was inside my house
فقد كانت تلك - المعلومات - في منزلي
and it was awesome.
وكانت رائعة
This was different
لقد كان هذا مختلفاً
than either generation had experienced before,
عما كان يمر به جيل والدي وجيل جدتي
and it changed the way I interacted with information
وقد غير الطريقة التي يتم فيها تناقل المعلومات
even at just a small level.
حتى على المستوى الادنى - مستوى الافراد -
But the information was closer to me.
لقد كانت المعلومات قريبة مني
I could get access to it.
بصورة استطيع الاطلاع عليها
In the time that passes
وفي الفترة التي مرت
between when I was a kid in high school
بين كوني طالبة مدرسة في المدرسة الثانوية
and when I started teaching,
وبين تلك التي أصبحت ادرس فيها
we really see the advent of the Internet.
رأينا ظهور الانترنت الفعلي
Right about the time that the Internet gets going
في الوقت الذي انطلق فيه الانترنت
as an educational tool,
ليصبح وسيلة تعليم
I take off from Wisconsin
انطلقت انا من وينسكونسون
and move to Kansas, small town Kansas,
الى كنساس .. الى مدينة صغيرة في كنساس
where I had an opportunity to teach
حيث تسنت لي فرصة التدريس
in a lovely, small-town,
بصورة رائعة في مدينة صغيرة
rural Kansas school district,
في مدرسة مقاطعة رارال كانساس
where I was teaching my favorite subject,
حيث كنت حينها ادرس مادتي المفضلة
American government.
السياسة الامريكية
My first year -- super gung-ho -- going to teach American government,
كنت سعيدة جدا لانه في عامي الاول سوف ادرس السياسة الامريكية
loved the political system.
كنت احب النظام السياسي
Kids in the 12th grade:
وكان الاطفال في الصف ال12
not exactly all that enthusiastic
ليسوا متحمسين جداً
about the American government system.
حيال النظام الامريكي الحكومي
Year two: learned a few things -- had to change my tactic.
وفي السنة الثانية بدأت اتعلم امورا جديدة .. جعلتني اغير طريقة تعاملي مع الامور
And I put in front of them an authentic experience
واضع في المقدمة تجربة اصلية
that allowed them to learn for themselves.
جعلتهم - الطلاب - يتعلمون من انفسهم
I didn't tell them what to do or how to do it.
لم اكن اخبرهم ماذا يفعلون او كيف يفعلون
I posed a problem in front of them,
كنت انقل لهم المشكلة لكي يقوموا بحلها
which was to put on an election forum for their own community.
كان مطلوب منهم صناعة نموذج انتخاب لبلدتهم
They produced flyers. They called offices.
حيث كان عليهم انتاج لوحات الترويج .. وتهيئة المكاتب
They checked schedules. They were meeting with secretaries.
وتدقيق المواعيد لمقابلة اعضاء مجلس الشيوخ
They produced an election forum booklet
وخرج البعض بقائمة طلبات سياسية
for the entire town to learn more about their candidates.
من مجتمعهم وتعلموا الكثير عن مرشحيهم
They invited everyone into the school
حيث تم دعوة الكثير منهم الى المدرسة
for an evening of conversation
من اجل حوار مسائي
about government and politics
عن الحكومة والسياسة
and whether or not the streets were done well,
وعن أوضاع تسوية الطرقات
and really had this robust experiential learning.
وكانت فعلاً هذه التجربة إستثنائية في التدريس
The older teachers -- more experienced --
حينها قالت لي احدى المدرسات القديمات
looked at me and went,
والتي كانت ذات خبرة كبيرة
"Oh, there she is. That's so cute. She's trying to get that done."
" ها .. ها هي .. رائعة جداً ... تظن انها يمكنها تغير شيء ما .. "
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"She doesn't know what she's in for."
" .. لا تعلم مالذي تقوم به .. "
But I knew that the kids would show up,
ولكني كنت أعلم .. ان الاطفال سوف يتعلمون
and I believed it,
وقد آمنت بذلك
and I told them every week what I expected out of them.
كنت أخبرهم كل اسبوع مالذي كنت اتوقعه منهم
And that night, all 90 kids --
وكانت كل ليلة كل الاطفال ال90
dressed appropriately, doing their job, owning it.
يرتدون ملابس رسمية .. لكي يقوموا بعملهم .. ويتقنوه
I had to just sit and watch.
كان علي فحسب ان اجلس واشاهد
It was theirs. It was experiential. It was authentic.
لقد كانت تجربتهم .. لقد كانت تجربة متفاعلة اصيلة
It meant something to them.
لقد عنت شيئاً بالنسبة لهم
And they will step up.
وقد رفعتهم الى مستوى جديد
From Kansas, I moved on to lovely Arizona,
من ولاية كنساس .. انتقلت الى ولاية أريزونا
where I taught in Flagstaff for a number of years,
حيث درست في فلاجستاف لعدة سنوات
this time with middle school students.
هذه المرة مع طلاب المدرسة المتوسطة
Luckily, I didn't have to teach them American government.
لحسن الحظ لم يكن يتوجب علي ان ادرسهم السياسة الامريكية
Could teach them the more exciting topic of geography.
وكان علي ان ادرس قسماً من الجغرافيا
Again, "thrilled" to learn.
وكنت مرة أخرى .. متحمسة جداً للتعليم
But what was interesting
ولكن الذي كان ممتعاً
about this position I found myself in in Arizona,
في هذا المنصب في أريزونا
was I had this really
هو انني ..
extraordinarily eclectic group of kids to work with
كنت ادرس مجموعة انتقائية مميزة من الطلاب
in a truly public school,
في المدرسة الحكومية تلك
and we got to have these moments where we would get these opportunities.
علينا ان نرى تلك اللحظات التي يتوجب فيها استغلال الفرص
And one opportunity
وكانت احدى الفرص تلك
was we got to go and meet Paul Rusesabagina,
هو اننا ذهبنا لرؤية باول روسيساباجينا
which is the gentleman
والذي كان رجلاً خلوقاً
that the movie "Hotel Rwanda" is based after.
والذي أُلف عنه فلم " فندق راوندا "
And he was going to speak at the high school next door to us.
وكان سيلقي خطاباً في المدرسة الثانوية التي تقع بقبرنا
We could walk there. We didn't even have to pay for the buses.
وكان يمكننا ان نسير الى هناك .. دون ان نستخدم الباصات
There was no expense cost. Perfect field trip.
اي لم يكن هنالك تكاليف ميدانية .. كانت الرحلة الافضل
The problem then becomes
ولكن كانت المشكلة حينها
how do you take seventh- and eighth-graders to a talk about genocide
كيف يمكن ان نأخذ طلاب الصف السابع والثامن للتحدث الى خطاب عن المجازر
and deal with the subject in a way
وجعلهم يتعاملون من الموضوع
that is responsible and respectful,
بمسؤولية وباحترام
and they know what to do with it.
وان يعرفوا كيف يستفيدوا من هذا
And so we chose to look at Paul Rusesabagina
لذا اخترنا ان ننظر الى باول روسيساباجينا
as an example of a gentleman
كمثال عن رجل خلوق
who singularly used his life to do something positive.
صمم ان يجعل حياته وسيلة للقيام بأمر إيجابي
I then challenged the kids to identify
ومن ثم تحديت الاطفال لكي يجدوا
someone in their own life, or in their own story, or in their own world,
أحداً بين عائلتهم او في عالمهم او محيطهم
that they could identify that had done a similar thing.
قام بالامر ذاته .. ويمكنهم التعريف به
I asked them to produce a little movie about it.
وقد طلبت منهم صنع فلم قصير عن ذلك
It's the first time we'd done this.
في المرة الاولى التي بدأنا العمل على هذا
Nobody really knew how to make these little movies on the computer,
لم يكن هناك من يعرف كيفية صناعة الافلام الصغيرة على الحاسوب
but they were into it. And I asked them to put their own voice over it.
ولكنهم كانوا مصرين على الامر .. واخبرتهم ان يكون التعليق على الفلم بصوتهم هم ..
It was the most awesome moment of revelation
لقد كانت تجربة رائعة جداً .. كشفت لي الكثير ..
that when you ask kids to use their own voice
حيث عندما طلبت من الاطفال استخدام اصواتهم
and ask them to speak for themselves,
وطلبت منهم التحدث عن انفسهم
what they're willing to share.
لم يكن همهم سوى الاجابة
The last question of the assignment is:
على السؤال الاخير من المهمة
how do you plan to use your life
والذي كان : ما هو مخطط لجعل حياتك
to positively impact other people?
ذات تأثير إيجابي على المحيط من حولك ؟
The things that kids will say
ان تلك الامور التي يقولها الاطفال
when you ask them and take the time to listen
بعد ان تسمح لهم بالوقت الكافي للتفكير ..
is extraordinary.
هي امورٌ رائعة ..
Fast-forward to Pennsylvania, where I find myself today.
وبالانتقال الى بنسيلفينا .. الولاية التي اعمل بها اليوم
I teach at the Science Leadership Academy,
حيث ادرس في أكاديمية العلوم المتقدمة
which is a partnership school between the Franklin Institute
وهي عبارة عن هيئة تدرسية لها صلة بمؤسسة فرانكلين
and the school district of Philadelphia.
ومدرسة مقاطعة فيلاديلفيا
We are a nine through 12 public school,
حيث نحن واحدة من 12 مدرسة حكومية تنتمي لتلك المؤسسة
but we do school quite differently.
ولكننا نقوم بالتدريس بصورة مختلفة
I moved there primarily
لقد قررت الاستقرار هناك
to be part of a learning environment
لكي اكون جزء من البيئة التعليمية
that validated the way that I knew that kids learned,
والتي تتصرف بصورة أعي انها سوف تعلم الاطفال
and that really wanted to investigate
والتي كانت - البيئة - تريد ان تكتشف
what was possible
مالذي يمكن الحصول عليه
when you are willing to let go
عندما نرغب في التخلي
of some of the paradigms of the past,
عن بعض امثلة الماضي
of information scarcity when my grandmother was in school
والتي كانت فيها المعلومات شحيحة .. كما في مدرسة جدتي
and when my father was in school and even when I was in school,
وكما في مدرسة والدي .. ومدرستي ايضا
and to a moment when we have information surplus.
والى اللحظة التي اصبحت فيه الحياة تعيش دفقاً من المعلومات
So what do you do when the information is all around you?
إذا ماذا يمكننا ان نفعل عندما تحيط بنا المعلومات من كل جهة ؟
Why do you have kids come to school
لماذا مازال يتوجب على الطلاب القدوم الى المدرسة
if they no longer have to come there to get the information?
اذا لم تعد هي المكان الذي منه تستجلب المعلومات ؟
In Philadelphia we have a one-to-one laptop program,
في فيلاديلفيا لدينا نظام " كمبيوتر شخصي ل كمبيوتر شخصي "
so the kids are bringing in laptops with them everyday,
لذا يجلب الطلاب معهم كمبيوتراتهم المحمولة الى المدرسة كل يوم
taking them home, getting access to information.
ويأخذوها معهم الى منازلهم .. لكي يستخدموها كوسيلة حصول على المعلومات
And here's the thing that you need to get comfortable with
وهناك شيء يجب ان تتأقلم معه حيال هذا
when you've given the tool
عندما تعطي للطالب آداة
to acquire information to students,
لكي تجلب المعلومات للطلاب
is that you have to be comfortable with this idea
هو انه يجب ان تكون منفتحاً على فكرة
of allowing kids to fail
ان الطلاب يسمح لهم بالفشل
as part of the learning process.
كجزء من العملية التعليمية
We deal right now in the educational landscape
نحن اليوم نتعامل مع مفهوم شاسع للتعليم
with an infatuation
ومع تأثير
with the culture of one right answer
ثقافة المنظور الاحادي للامور
that can be properly bubbled on the average multiple choice test,
والتي يمكن ان تظهر في امتحانات الخيارات المتعددة
and I am here to share with you:
وانا هنا لكي اقول لكم ..
it is not learning.
ان هذا ليس تعليماً
That is the absolute wrong thing to ask,
انه الطريق الاسوء للتعليم
to tell kids to never be wrong.
اي ان نخبر الطلاب . انه لا يجب ان يخطئوا .. بحكم منظور الاجابة الاحادية
To ask them to always have the right answer
وان نطلب منهم دوماً معرفة الاجابة الصحيحة
doesn't allow them to learn.
هي ليست وسيلة صحيحة للتعليم ..
So we did this project,
وما قمنا به في هذا المشروع
and this is one of the artifacts of the project.
هذه واحدة من التوضيحات المتعلقة بالمشروع
I almost never show them off
والتي لم اظهرها على الاطلاق
because of the issue of the idea of failure.
بسبب الفكرة المنتشرة عن الفشل
My students produced these info-graphics
لقد صنع طلابي هذه المعلومات
as a result of a unit that we decided to do at the end of the year
كنتيجة لما قررنا ان نقوم به في نهاية العام
responding to the oil spill.
في خصوص التسرب النفطي
I asked them to take the examples that we were seeing
اخبرتهم ان يعتمدوا على المعلومات
of the info-graphics that existed
التي كانت في الاساس موجودة
in a lot of mass media,
ضمن نطاق الاعلام والتعويم الاعلامي الذي حدث
and take a look at what were the interesting components of it,
والنظر الى العناصر المثيرة للاهتمام الموجودة فيها
and produce one for themselves
ومن ثم صنع خاصتهم
of a different man-made disaster from American history.
المتعلقة بأزمة أخرى من صنع الانسان في تاريخ الولايات المتحدة الامريكية
And they had certain criteria to do it.
اي تم تخصيصهم ضمن نطاق صغير
They were a little uncomfortable with it,
ولم يكونوا مرتاحين مع الفكرة بكثرة
because we'd never done this before, and they didn't know exactly how to do it.
لانهم لم يقوموا بهذا من ذي قبل .. ولم يكن لديهم اي فكرة عما يجب القيام به
They can talk -- they're very smooth,
فهم طلقاء في التحدث
and they can write very, very well,
ويملكون البلاغة في الكتابة
but asking them to communicate ideas in a different way
ولكن ان تطلب منهم تبادل المعلومات بصورة أخرى ..
was a little uncomfortable for them.
كان امراً جديداً وغير مريح بالنسبة لهم
But I gave them the room to just do the thing.
ولكن بهذه الطريقة اعطيتهم مجالاً للقيام بشيء
Go create. Go figure it out.
إخترعوا .. اكتشفوا .. تحركوا ..
Let's see what we can do.
لنرى مالذي يمكننا القيام به
And the student that persistently
والطالب الذي قدم العرض المرئي الافضل
turns out the best visual product did not disappoint.
كان عرضه مرض جداً
This was done in like two or three days.
وقد قام به بيومين او ثلاث فحسب
And this is the work of the student that consistently did it.
وهو عمل يمكن للطالب القيام به على الدوام
And when I sat the students down, I said, "Who's got the best one?"
وعندما جلست مع الطلاب سوية نستعرض المشاريع .. وسئلتهم .. أي العروض افضل
And they immediately went, "There it is."
لقد قالوا على الفور .. هذا هو ..
Didn't read anything. "There it is."
مباشرة .. هذا هو ..
And I said, "Well what makes it great?"
فقلت .. حسنا .. مالذي يجعله رائعا هكذا ..
And they're like, "Oh, the design's good, and he's using good color.
فقالوا .. حسنا .. التصميم رائع .. الالوان متناسقة
And there's some ... " And they went through all that we processed out loud.
ومن ثم استعرضنا كل العملية والعروض التي قمنا بها ..
And I said, "Go read it."
وقلت لهم .. لنمر سوية على الابحاث التي قدمت .. ..
And they're like, "Oh, that one wasn't so awesome."
فقال أحدهم .. لا لا .. ليس بخيار جيد .. " واصفاً احد الابحاث "
And then we went to another one --
ومن ثم انتقلنا الى آخر ..
it didn't have great visuals, but it had great information --
لم يكن يملك صورا او عناصر توضيحية رائعة .. ولكنه كان غني بالمعلومات الرائعة
and spent an hour talking about the learning process,
و من ثم جلسنا لساعة نتحدث عن العملية التعليمية
because it wasn't about whether or not it was perfect,
لان الامر لم يكن عما اذا كان المشروع الذي قدم " العرض " مثالي ام لا ..
or whether or not it was what I could create.
او هل كان هو الذي في مخيلتي الذي ابحث عنه كمدرسة
It asked them to create for themselves,
فهذا المشروع في الاساس للطلاب ..
and it allowed them to fail,
وكان يسمح لهم ان يفشلوا فيه ..
process, learn from.
وان يعدلوا طريقته .. وان نظم التعليم المُتأتية منه
And when we do another round of this in my class this year,
وعندما سنقوم بمشروع ممثال هذا العام
they will do better this time,
انا واثقة انهم سوف يؤدون العمل على نحو أفضل
because learning
لان التعليم
has to include an amount of failure,
يتوجب ان يحوي امكانية للفشل ..
because failure is instructional
لان الفشل .. موجه .. ودافع .. ومفيد
in the process.
في العملية التعليمية ..
There are a million pictures
هنالك مليون صورة
that I could click through here,
يمكنني ان اعرضها لكم هنا
and had to choose carefully -- this is one of my favorites --
وكان علي ان اختار بعناية بضعاً منها .. وقد اخترت هذه .. انها المفضلة لدي
of students learning,
عن الطلاب وهم يتعلمون
of what learning can look like
او كيف يمكن ان يكون التعليم عليه
in a landscape where we let go of the idea
في المنحى العام .. عندما نسمح للافكار بالخروج ونعطيها الحرية لذلك
that kids have to come to school to get the information,
هؤلاء الاطفال لك يأتوا الى المدرسة لكي يكتسبوا المعلومات
but instead, ask them what they can do with it.
ولكن جائوا لكي يتعلموا مالذي يمكن القيام به بواسطة هذه المعلومات
Ask them really interesting questions.
ولكي يتعلوما كيفية طرح الاسئلة المثيرة للاهتمام
They will not disappoint.
وعدم فقدان الامل
Ask them to go to places,
والذهاب الى الاماكن
to see things for themselves,
لرؤية المعلومات والامور بأم اعينهم
to actually experience the learning,
لكي يعيشوا التعليم حقاً
to play, to inquire.
لكي يلعبوا .. لكي يحققوا
This is one of my favorite photos,
هذه واحدة من الصور المفضلة لدي ..
because this was taken on Tuesday,
لانها أُلتقطن يوم الثلاثاء
when I asked the students to go to the polls.
عندما طلب من الطلاب الذهاب الى الانتخابات
This is Robbie, and this was his first day of voting,
هذا هو .. روب .. انه تصويته الاول ..
and he wanted to share that with everybody and do that.
وكان يريد ان يشارك هذا الامر مع الجميع
But this is learning too,
ولكن هذا امرٌ يندرج ضمن التعليم ايضاً
because we asked them to go out into real spaces.
لاننا نطلب منهم الذهاب الى اماكن حقيقية واقعية
The main point
هذه هي الفكرة الرئيسية
is that, if we continue to look at education
فنحن ان بقينا ننظر الى التعليم
as if it's about coming to school
كما لو انه مجرد الذهاب الى المدرسة
to get the information
للحصول على المعلومات
and not about experiential learning,
وليس كأنه تعليم تجريبي عملي واقعي
empowering student voice and embracing failure,
يقدس وجهة نظر التطالب .. ويحترم فشله
we're missing the mark.
فنحن نفقد المعنى الحقيقي للتعليم
And everything that everybody is talking about today
وهو الامر الذي يتحدث عنه الجميع اليوم ..
isn't possible if we keep having an educational system
ومن غير المنطقي ان نبقي على نظام تعليمي
that does not value these qualities,
لا يقدس هذه المزايا
because we won't get there with a standardized test,
لاننا لن نصل الى مستوى تعليمي مميز بواسطة اختبار قبول الجامعات فحسب
and we won't get there with a culture of one right answer.
ولن نصل الى ذلك بمفهوم الاجابة الصحيحة الاحادية
We know how to do this better,
ونحن نعرف كيف يمكننا ان نحسن ذلك الامر . وكيف نرتقي بالتعليم
and it's time to do better.
وهذا هو الوقت الاكثر ملائمة للقيام بذلك
(Applause)
(تصفيق)